{
	"allQuestions": [{
			"id": 0,
			"question": "Android is -",
			"category": "android",
			"answer": [
				"a web browser",
				"an operating system",
				"a web server",
				"None of the above"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "an operating system"
		},
		{
			"id": 1,
			"question": "Under which of the following Android is licensed?",
			"category": "android",
			"answer": [
				"OSS",
				"OSS",
				"Apache/MIT",
				"None of the above"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Apache/MIT"
		},
		{
			"id": 2,
			"question": " For which of the following Android is mainly developed?",
			"category": "android",
			"answer": [
				"Mobile devices",
				"Watch",
				"Desktops",
				"Servers"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Mobile devices"
		},
		{
			"id": 3,
			"question": "Which of the following is the first mobile phone released that ran the Android OS?",
			"category": "android",
			"answer": [
				"Google gPhone",
				"T - Mobile G1",
				"Samsung",
				"Motorola"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "T - Mobile G1"
		},
		{
			"id": 4,
			"question": "Which of the following virtual machine is used by the Android operating system?",
			"category": "android",
			"answer": [
				"Simple virtual machine",
				"JVM",
				"Dalvik virtual machine",
				"None of the above"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Dalvik virtual machine"
		},
		{
			"id": 5,
			"question": "APK stands for -",
			"answer": [
				"Android Page Kit",
				"Android Phone Kit",
				"Android Package Kit",
				"None of the above"
			],
			"category": "android",
			"correctAnswer": "Android Package Kit"
		},
		{
			"id": 6,
			"question": "What does API stand for?",
			"answer": [
				"Application Page Interface",
				"Application Programming Interface",
				"Android Programming Interface",
				"Android Page Interface"
			],
			"category": "android",
			"correctAnswer": "Application Programming Interface"
		},
		{
			"id": 7,
			"question": "Which of the following converts Java byte code into Dalvik byte code?",
			"answer": [
				"Dex compiler",
				"Virtual Machine",
				"Mobile interpretive compiler (MIC)",
				"Dalvik converter"
			],
			"category": "android",
			"correctAnswer": "Dex compiler"
		},
		{
			"id": 8,
			"question": "How can we stop the services in android?",
			"answer": [
				"By using system.exit() method",
				"By using the stopSelf() and stopService() method",
				"By using system.exit() method",
				"By using system.stop() method"
			],
			"category": "android",
			"correctAnswer": "By using the stopSelf() and stopService() method"
		},
		{
			"id": 9,
			"question": "What is an activity in android?",
			"answer": [
				"android package",
				"android resourse",
				"android class",
				"A single screen in an application with supporting java/kotlin code"
			],
			"category": "android",
			"correctAnswer": "A single screen in an application with supporting java/kotlin code"
		},
		{
			"id": 10,
			"question": "How can we kill an activity in android?",
			"answer": [
				"Using finishActivity(int requestCode)",
				"Using finish() method",
				"Neither (a) nor (b)",
				"Both (a) and (b)"
			],
			"category": "android",
			"correctAnswer": "Both (a) and (b)"
		},
		{
			"id": 11,
			"question": "ADB stands for -",
			"answer": [
				"Android destroy bridge",
				"Android delete bridge",
				"Android debug bridge",
				"None of the above"
			],
			"category": "android",
			"correctAnswer": "Android debug bridge"
		},
		{
			"id": 12,
			"question": "On which of the following, developers can test the application, during developing the android applications?",
			"answer": [
				"Physical android phone",
				"Third-party emulators",
				"Emulator included in Android SDK",
				"All of the above"
			],
			"category": "android",
			"correctAnswer": "All of the above"
		},
		{
			"id": 13,
			"question": "Which of the following kernel is used in Android?",
			"answer": [
				"Redhat",
				"Linux",
				"Windows",
				"MAC"
			],
			"category": "android",
			"correctAnswer": "Linux"
		},
		{
			"id": 14,
			"question": "Which of the following is the first callback method that is invoked by the system during an activity life-cycle?",
			"answer": [
				"onRestart() method",
				"onStart() method",
				"onCreate() method",
				"onAttach() method"
			],
			"category": "android",
			"correctAnswer": "onCreate() method"
		},
		{
			"id": 15,
			"question": "Which of the following is not an activity lifecycle callback method?",
			"answer": [
				"onCreate() method",
				"onBackPressed() method",
				"onResume() method",
				"onCreate() method"
			],
			"category": "android",
			"correctAnswer": "onBackPressed() method"
		},
		{
			"id": 16,
			"question": "We require an AVD to create an emulator. What does AVD stand for?",
			"answer": [
				"Android Virtual device",
				"Active Virtual display",
				"Android Virtual display",
				"Android Virtual display"
			],
			"category": "android",
			"correctAnswer": "Android Virtual device"
		},
		{
			"id": 17,
			"question": "Does android support other languages than java?",
			"answer": [
				"Can't Say",
				"No",
				"Yes",
				"May be "
			],
			"category": "android",
			"correctAnswer": "Yes"
		},
		{
			"id": 18,
			"question": "What is the use of content provider in Android?",
			"answer": [
				"For sending the data from an application to another application",
				"For sending messages to other application",
				"For storing the data in the database",
				"For sending the data from an application to another application"
			],
			"category": "android",
			"correctAnswer": "For sending the data from an application to another application"
		},
		{
			"id": 19,
			"question": "AAPT stands for -",
			"answer": [
				"Android Action Packaging Tool",
				"Android Activity Packaging Tool",
				"Android Asset Packaging Tool",
				"None of the above"
			],
			"category": "android",
			"correctAnswer": "Android Asset Packaging Tool"
		},
		{
			"id": 20,
			"question": "NDK stands for -",
			"answer": [
				"Native Development Kit",
				"New Development kit",
				"Native Design Kit",
				"None of the above"
			],
			"category": "android",
			"correctAnswer": "Native Development Kit"
		},
		{
			"id": 21,
			"question": "Which of the following is contained in the src folder?",
			"answer": [
				"Manifest",
				"Java source code",
				"XML",
				"None of the above"
			],
			"category": "android",
			"correctAnswer": "Java source code"
		},
		{
			"id": 22,
			"question": "Which of the following method is used to handle what happens after clicking a button?",
			"answer": [
				"onCreate",
				"onSelect",
				"onClick",
				"onClicked"
			],
			"category": "android",
			"correctAnswer": "onClick"
		},
		{
			"id": 23,
			"question": "Which of the following android component displays the part of an activity on screen?",
			"answer": [
				"Intent",
				"Fragment",
				"Service",
				"Intent"
			],
			"category": "android",
			"correctAnswer": "Fragment"
		},
		{
			"id": 24,
			"question": "In which of the following tab an error is shown?",
			"answer": [
				"Profiler",
				"Logcat",
				"CPU",
				"Memory"
			],
			"category": "android",
			"correctAnswer": "Logcat"
		},
		{
			"id": 25,
			"question": "Which of the following is the topmost layer of android architecture?",
			"answer": [
				"System Libraries and Android Runtime",
				"Applications Framework",
				"Applications",
				"Linux Kernel"
			],
			"category": "android",
			"correctAnswer": "Applications"
		},
		{
			"id": 26,
			"question": "Which of the layer is the lowest layer of android architecture?",
			"answer": [
				"Applications",
				"Applications Framework",
				"Linux Kernel",
				"System Libraries and Android Runtime"
			],
			"category": "android",
			"correctAnswer": "Linux Kernel"
		},
		{
			"id": 27,
			"question": "What is contained in manifest.xml?",
			"answer": [
				"List of strings used in the app",
				"Source code",
				"App assests",
				"Permission that the application requires"
			],
			"category": "android",
			"correctAnswer": "Permission that the application requires"
		},
		{
			"id": 28,
			"question": "Which of the following is not a state in the service lifecycle?",
			"answer": [
				"Paused",
				"Destroyed",
				"Running",
				"Start"
			],
			"category": "android",
			"correctAnswer": "Paused"
		},
		{
			"id": 29,
			"question": "Which of the following is not a nickname of any android version?",
			"answer": [
				"Honeycomb",
				"Muffin",
				"Donut",
				"Cupcake"
			],
			"category": "android",
			"correctAnswer": "Muffin"
		},
		{
			"id": 30,
			"question": "Which of the following is a dialog class in android?",
			"answer": [
				"AlertDialog",
				"DatePicker Dialog",
				"AlertDialog",
				"All of the above"
			],
			"category": "android",
			"correctAnswer": "All of the above"
		},
		{
			"id": 31,
			"question": "Dummy",
			"category": "android",
			"answer": [
				"df",
				"sd"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "df",
			"options": [
				"df",
				"sd"
			]
		},
		{
			"id": 32,
			"question": "Which of the following is a dialog class in android?",
			"category": "android",
			"answer": [
				"ProgressDialog",
				"AlertDialog",
				"DatePicker Dialog",
				"All of the above"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "All of the above"
		},
		{
			"id": 33,
			"question": "In which state the activity is, if it is not in focus, but still visible on the screen?",
			"category": "android",
			"answer": [
				"Paused state",
				"Destroyed state",
				"Rest State",
				"Running state"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Paused state"
		},
		{
			"id": 34,
			"question": "Which of the following is the built-in database of Android?",
			"category": "android",
			"answer": [
				"Oracle",
				"MySQL",
				"SQLite",
				"MongoDB"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "SQLite"
		},
		{
			"id": 35,
			"question": "Android is developed by ",
			"category": "android",
			"answer": [
				"Samsung",
				"Microsoft",
				"Google",
				"Android Inc"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Android Inc"
		},
		{
			"id": 36,
			"question": "Android Web Browser Is Based On",
			"category": "android",
			"answer": [
				"Open-source Webkit",
				"Chrome",
				"Firefox",
				"Safari"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Open-source Webkit"
		},
		{
			"id": 37,
			"question": "Which Media Format Is Not Supported By Android",
			"category": "android",
			"answer": [
				"AVI",
				"MPEG",
				"MP4",
				"MIDI"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "AVI"
		},
		{
			"id": 38,
			"question": "In Which Directory  XML Layout Files Are Stored",
			"category": "android",
			"answer": [
				"/res/values",
				"/res/layout",
				"/assets",
				"/src"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "/res/layout"
		},
		{
			"id": 39,
			"question": "View Pager Is Used For",
			"category": "android",
			"answer": [
				"Paging Down List Items",
				"Swiping Activities",
				"Paging Down List Items",
				"Swiping Fragments"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Swiping Fragments"
		},
		{
			"id": 40,
			"question": "What Is JNI In Android?",
			"category": "android",
			"answer": [
				"Image Editable Tool",
				"Java Network Interface",
				"Java Native Interface",
				"Java Interface"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Java Native Interface"
		},
		{
			"id": 41,
			"question": "ANR in android stands for -",
			"category": "android",
			"answer": [
				"Application Not Responding",
				"Application Not Rendering",
				"Application Not Reacting",
				"None of the above"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Application Not Responding"
		},
		{
			"id": 42,
			"question": "All layout classes are the subclasses of -",
			"category": "android",
			"answer": [
				"android.view.ViewGroup",
				"android.view.View",
				"android.widget",
				"None of the above"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "android.view.ViewGroup"
		},
		{
			"id": 43,
			"question": "Which of the following class in android executes the task asynchronously with your service?",
			"category": "android",
			"answer": [
				"AsyncTask",
				"SyncTask",
				"Both of the above",
				"Main Thread"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "AsyncTask"
		},
		{
			"id": 44,
			"question": "Which of the following layout in android arranges its children into rows and columns?",
			"category": "android",
			"answer": [
				"RowLayout",
				"FrameLayout",
				"TableLayout",
				"LinearLayout"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "TableLayout"
		},
		{
			"id": 45,
			"question": "Which of the following layout in android aligns all children either vertically or horizontally?",
			"category": "android",
			"answer": [
				"LinearLayout",
				"RelativeLayout",
				"TableLayout",
				"FrameLayout"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "LinearLayout"
		},
		{
			"id": 46,
			"question": "What is the default value of the orientation attribute in LinearLayout?",
			"category": "android",
			"answer": [
				"Vertical",
				"Horizontal",
				"There is no default value of orientation attribute in LinearLayout",
				"None of the above"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Horizontal"
		},
		{
			"id": 47,
			"question": "What is the nine-patch images tool in android?",
			"category": "android",
			"answer": [
				"It is an image extension tool.",
				"It is used to change the bitmap images into nine sections",
				"Both (a) and (b)",
				"Both (a) and (b)"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "It is used to change the bitmap images into nine sections"
		},
		{
			"id": 48,
			"question": "GCM in android stands for -",
			"category": "android",
			"answer": [
				"Google Count Messaging",
				"Google Center Messaging",
				"Google Cloud Messaging",
				"None of the above"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Google Cloud Messaging"
		},
		{
			"id": 49,
			"question": "Number of primitive data types in Java are?",
			"category": "java",
			"answer": [
				"6",
				"4",
				"5",
				"8"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "8"
		},
		{
			"id": 50,
			"question": "Automatic type conversion is possible in which of the possible cases?",
			"category": "java",
			"answer": [
				"Long to int",
				"Byte to int",
				"Int to long",
				"Short to int"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Int to long"
		},
		{
			"id": 51,
			"question": "Select the valid statement.",
			"category": "java",
			"answer": [
				"char[] ch = new char[5]",
				"char[] ch = new char()",
				"char[] ch = new char(5)",
				"char[] ch = new char[]"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "char[] ch = new char[5]"
		},
		{
			"id": 52,
			"question": "When an array is passed to a method, what does the method receive?",
			"category": "java",
			"answer": [
				"Copy of first element",
				"A copy of the array",
				"Length of the array",
				"The reference of the array"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "The reference of the array"
		},
		{
			"id": 53,
			"question": "Select the valid statement to declare and initialize an array.",
			"category": "java",
			"answer": [
				"int[] A = (1, 3, 5)",
				"int[] A = {}",
				"int[] A = {1, 3, 5}",
				"int[][] A = {1, 3, 5}"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "int[] A = {1, 3, 5}"
		},
		{
			"id": 54,
			"question": "When is the object created with new keyword?",
			"category": "java",
			"answer": [
				"At run time",
				"None",
				"Depends on the code",
				"At compile time"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "At run time"
		},
		{
			"id": 55,
			"question": "In which of the following is toString() method defined?",
			"category": "java",
			"answer": [
				"java.lang.util",
				"java.lang.Object",
				"java.lang.String",
				"None"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "java.lang.Object"
		},
		{
			"id": 56,
			"question": "what compareTo() returns?",
			"category": "java",
			"answer": [
				"An int value",
				"true",
				"false",
				"None"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "An int value"
		},
		{
			"id": 57,
			"question": "\nIdentify the return type of a method that does not return any value.",
			"category": "java",
			"answer": [
				"int",
				"main",
				"null",
				"void"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "void"
		},
		{
			"id": 58,
			"question": "Where does the system stores parameters and local variables whenever a method is invoked?",
			"category": "java",
			"answer": [
				"Stack",
				"Heap",
				"Tree",
				"Hash"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Stack"
		}, {
			"id": 0,
			"question": "Which animal is known as the (Ship of the Desert)?",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"Camel",
				"Dog",
				"Horse",
				"Lion"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Camel"
		},
		{
			"id": 1,
			"question": "How many hours are there in 1 day?",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"20 hours",
				"24 hours",
				"23 hours",
				"22 hours"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "24 hours"
		},
		{
			"id": 2,
			"question": "How many days are there in 1 week?",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"5 days",
				"8 days",
				"7 days",
				"6 days"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "7 days"
		},
		{
			"id": 3,
			"question": "How many letters are there in the English alphabet?",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"20 letters",
				"25 letters",
				"24 letters",
				"26 letters"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "26 letters"
		},
		{
			"id": 4,
			"question": "How many colours a rainbow have?",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"7 colours",
				"3 colours",
				"5 colours",
				"6 colours"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "7 colours"
		},
		{
			"id": 5,
			"question": "How many days are there in one year?",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"350 days",
				"365 days",
				"360 days",
				"355 days"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "365 days"
		},
		{
			"id": 6,
			"question": "How many minutes are there in one hour?",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"60 minutes",
				"30 minutes",
				"40 minutes",
				"70 minutes"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "60 minutes"
		},
		{
			"id": 7,
			"question": "How many centimetre are there in one meter? ",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"10 cm",
				"100 cm",
				"1000 cm",
				"1 cm"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "100 cm"
		},
		{
			"id": 8,
			"question": "How may meters in one kilometer?",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"100 m",
				"500 m",
				"1000 m",
				"10 m"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "1000 m"
		},
		{
			"id": 9,
			"question": "How many consonants are there in the English alphabet?",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"20",
				"22",
				"24",
				"21"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "21"
		},
		{
			"id": 10,
			"question": "How many vowels are there in the English alphabet?",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"5 vowels ",
				"7 vowels ",
				"8 vowels ",
				"4 vowels "
			],
			"correctAnswer": "5 vowels "
		},
		{
			"id": 11,
			"question": "Which animal is not a pet commonly?",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"A Dog",
				"A Cat",
				"A Goat",
				"A Lion"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "A Lion"
		},
		{
			"id": 12,
			"question": "Find the uncommon one?",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"Dog",
				"Cat",
				"Goat",
				"Shark"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Shark"
		},
		{
			"id": 13,
			"question": "Find the uncommon one?",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"Cricket",
				"Golf",
				"Footbal",
				"Kabaddi"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Kabaddi"
		},
		{
			"id": 14,
			"question": "Find the uncommon one?",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"Car",
				"Mobile",
				"Cycle",
				"Bus"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Mobile"
		},
		{
			"id": 15,
			"question": "Animal normally known as.. King of the Jungle",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"Tiger",
				"Fox",
				"Lion",
				"Elephant"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Lion"
		},
		{
			"id": 16,
			"question": "Capital of India?",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"Mumbai",
				"New Delhi",
				"Gandhinagar",
				"Bihar"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "New Delhi"
		},
		{
			"id": 17,
			"question": "Find the uncommon one?",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"India",
				"China",
				"US",
				"Bhopal"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Bhopal"
		},
		{
			"id": 18,
			"question": "Find the uncommon one?",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"Orange",
				"Green",
				"Blue",
				"Fish"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Fish"
		},
		{
			"id": 19,
			"question": "National animal of India",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"Tiger",
				"Elephant",
				"Horse",
				"Lion"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Tiger"
		},
		{
			"id": 20,
			"question": "National birt of India?",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"Peacock",
				"Pigeon",
				"Sparrow",
				"Eagle"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Peacock"
		},
		{
			"id": 21,
			"question": "National flower of India?",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"Rose",
				"Lotus",
				"Lily",
				"Sunflower"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Lotus"
		},
		{
			"id": 22,
			"question": "National fruit of India?",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"Orange",
				"Apple",
				"Banana",
				"Mango"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Mango"
		},
		{
			"id": 23,
			"question": "Name the primary colours?",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"Red, Yellow and Blue",
				"Green, Orange and Red",
				"Blue, White and Gray",
				"Green, Red and White"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Red, Yellow and Blue"
		},
		{
			"id": 24,
			"question": "Smallest month of the year?",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"March",
				"February",
				"October",
				"April"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "February"
		},
		{
			"id": 25,
			"question": "Who was the first Prime Minister of India?",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"Indira Gandhi",
				"Mahatma Gandhi",
				"Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel ",
				"Pandit Jawaharlal Nehru"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Pandit Jawaharlal Nehru"
		},
		{
			"id": 26,
			"question": "Which festival is called the festival of colours?",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"Diwali",
				"Holi",
				"Lohri",
				"Rakhi"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Holi"
		},
		{
			"id": 27,
			"question": "The national aquatic animal of India?",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"River Dolphin",
				"White cheeked shark",
				"Starfish",
				"Goldfish"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "River Dolphin"
		},
		{
			"id": 28,
			"question": "The planet known as the Red Planet?",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"Mercury",
				"Earth",
				"Jupiter",
				"Mars"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Mars"
		},
		{
			"id": 29,
			"question": "The country known as the Land of the Rising Sun?",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"Japan",
				"India",
				"USA",
				"Hong Kong"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Japan",
			"options": [
				"Japan",
				"India",
				"USA",
				"China"
			]
		},
		{
			"id": 30,
			"question": "How many millimeters are there in a centimeters?",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"15mm",
				"20mm",
				"1mm",
				"10mm"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "10mm"
		},
		{
			"id": 31,
			"question": "Name the hardest substance available on Earth?",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"Diamond",
				"Gold",
				"Iron",
				"Silver"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Diamond"
		},
		{
			"id": 32,
			"question": "Name the shape that has ten sides?",
			"category": "gk",
			"answer": [
				"Octagon",
				"Decagon",
				"Polygon",
				"Hexagon"
			],
			"correctAnswer": "Decagon"
		}
	]
}
